uesp.net 2018-12-24

# UESPWiki:Privacy Policy - The Unofficial Elder Scrolls Pages (UESP)

## Summary

The _Unofficial Elder Scrolls Pages_ (hereafter referred to as " _the UESP_ " or " _we_ ") is committed to respecting and protecting the privacy of its members and visitors. In order to allow said individuals a better understanding of our online practices concerning their privacy, we provide this notice explaining such.

It is important to note that this privacy policy applies strictly to _The Unofficial Elder Scrolls Pages_ and is not to be considered a reflection upon the policies or practices of any other site linked or alluded to herein.

### Consent

By visiting the UESP or making use of its services, you consent to the terms set forth in this policy.

### Changes

This policy may be regularly updated to encompass new aspects of the site, or supplemented to better accommodate the privacy of our members. For this reason, we urge our members and visitors to regularly consult this notice for changes. Continued access or use of this website thereafter shall constitute an express acceptance of any modifications.

## Publishing on the UESP

The act of editing any portion of the website, regardless of size, is considered an act of publication. All publications made on the UESP will openly display the username of the publisher (for registered members) or the IP (Internet Protocol) address of the published (for non-registered members).

### Identity

Upon submission of an edit, your username and IP address will be recorded along with the information you have submitted. If you have registered on the site and logged in, only your username will be publicly displayed; places where your username appear include the "history" tab of the article you have edited, your "contributions" list, and the "Recent Changes" directory. If you have not registered on the site, your IP address will be displayed in place of a username in all of these locations. If you wish to prevent your IP address from being displayed, you should create an account and edit under that account.

For registered editors, the IP addresses of all edits are also recorded in the Recent changes log. This information is stored for a period of one week. Access to the IP addresses in the Recent changes log is restricted to administrators only. These IP addresses are not normally made public, although administrators may post the information on the user talk page in cases where the user has vandalized the site and is suspected of being a repeat offender.

### Cookies

The UESP sets a temporary session cookie (PHPSESSID) within your computer each time you visit the site. This cookie may be denied via in-browser settings, however, without such you will be unable to login. Upon logging in, further cookies may be added in order to store the data necessary to prevent a new login upon each page transition from being necessitated. Should the option to have your username and password stored against input on your next visit be checked, a long-term cookie will be set within your computer, lasting for the duration of thirty days. This cookie may be deleted at any time by clearing the in-browser cookie cache. All other cookies are deleted automatically upon logging off the UESP or exiting your browser session.

### Passwords

The integrity of a user account is maintained first and foremost by the password protecting it. This password remains the sole domain of the user having created the account, and will not be made publicly available under any circumstance. No administrator will ever request your password, and because passwords are encrypted into the database, it will remain secret.

## User Data

### Minors

As neither registration, nor the associated benefits of such, with the UESP requires the submission of any form of personally identifiable information, minors under the age of thirteen (13) are free to join the UESP, except when they are not legally able to do so. As we do not monitor edits prior to their publication, and as we allow the submission of potentially offensive material, the parent or guardian of each minor is ultimately responsible for their conduct on our site and what they view.

### Removal of Accounts

The ability to remove user accounts is limited solely to the administrators of the site or sub-section. User accounts will not be removed regardless of their respective activity, and the removal of an account may be denied should a request for such be submitted. An account will only be deleted if its presence constitutes a liability to the integrity of the site, or infringes upon local or national laws.

For wiki accounts in particular a user can themselves remove all identifying information by editing/removing their real name and e-mail. In cases where the wiki username contains identifying personal information we can rename accounts on request. Users who lose access to their accounts can request manual removal/renaming if sufficient evidence of account ownership can be provided.

### Data Logs

The UESP server routinely maintains access logs detailing page visits and user-related information. These logs are regularly consulted in order to derive the popularity of, links connected to, and web browser used to access pages on the site. Outside of such, the UESP does not make use of the information contained in these logs, save in the following situations:

  * In the course of regular technical maintenance.
  * In order to investigate abuse of the wiki.
  * In order to protect the integrity of the UESP or privacy of its users.
  * When given permission by the target user.

### Disclosure

The disclosure of information regarding any members or visitor may take place under the following circumstances:

  * To protect our site against liability or to prevent fraudulent activity.
  * Where it is necessary to limit any damage as a result of vandalism or related activities.
  * To effect a transaction in connection with the sale, merger, spin-off, or other reorganization of the site.
  * Where the information is in the public domain.

In any of the above-noted circumstances, public notice of this disclosure will be posted.

In certain circumstances, however, the UESP will disclose information related to any member or visitor without their consent where the disclosure of such information may be justified or permitted. Such circumstances include:

  * If required to comply with a subpoena, warrant, or order issued by a court of law or body with the jurisdiction to compel the production of said information.
  * If we receive a formal request to disclose your information in connection with a legal action; under said circumstances, and if permitted by law, we will attempt to notify you of such prior to responding to the request.
  * If we believe in good faith that a law, regulation, rule or guideline requires it.
  * If the release of said information will negate the emergency of a situation that threatens the life, health, or security of an identifiable person or group.

Save in the above-noted circumstances, data derived from any source regarding the UESP's members or visitors will never be publicly distributed or made available.

## Third Parties

Save where otherwise specified, all materials within the UESP are made available under the terms of the Attribution-ShareAlike 2.5 License, and are open to distribution, display, public performance, and the creation of derivate works by any third party. The UESP will not, however, sell this information, nor data regarding any of our members or visitors to any third party. Furthermore, the UESP will take appropriate action against any third party which attempts to make use of said information for personal or commercial gain.

## Links

For the convenience of our members, users, and visitors, and in an effort to provide sources for the information contained in the UESP, links are regularly provided to other sites. Access to any site via a link provided on the UESP entails a removal from the UESP; thereafter, all activities upon said sites are considered under the privacy policy of the respective site, and for such the UESP acknowledges no responsibility. We urge our members, users, and visitors to carefully consult the privacy policies of linked sites prior to making use of their services.

## Security

The UESP employs physical, administrative, and technical safeguards to protect the confidentiality and integrity of the site and information contained therein. All information submitted to the site is maintained, regardless of edits made thereafter to such, and may be recovered at any time by an administrator with the appropriate access.

## Extensions

The UESP maintains official extensions of the site, through which users, visitors, and members may interact and converse with others.

### Forum

The UESP [forums](http://www.uesp.net/phpbb/) are made publicly available, although registration is required to post therein. The terms of this policy apply to said forums, insofar as applicable.

### Blog

The UESP [blog](http://blog.uesp.net/). The terms of this policy apply to said blog, insofar as applicable.

### Discord

The UESP Discord server for text chatting. The terms of this policy apply to Discord , insofar as applicable.

## Advertising

The UESP uses [Curse](https://www.curse.com/advertising) and [Google AdSense](http://www.google.com/adsense) to provide advertisements in order to assist with running costs. This system is not under the control of UESP and may record details and / or store cookies in addition to the recording and storage described above. Further details are available on the [Curse Privacy Policy](https://www.twitch.tv/p/legal/privacy-policy/), the [AdSense site](http://www.google.com/adsense), and in Google's [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/privacy.html).

Google Adsense in particular (taken from [Google Advertising Cookie and Privacy Policies](http://www.google.com/adsense/support/bin/answer.py?answer=100557&sourceid=aso&subid=ww-ww-et-asui&medium=link):

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site.
  * Google's use of the [Double Click DART cookie](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx) enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and [content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

## Questions

If you have questions or concerns regarding this policy, or the privacy practices of the UESP, please contact an administrator via the contact page. If you fail to receive acknowledgment of your inquiry, or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, notice of such should be posted on the Community Portal.
